A Guide to the University of Connecticut, Research Foundation Records 1980.0031
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
University of Connecticut, Research Foundation Records
1950-2001
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
1980.0031
13 Linear Feet
The collection consists of the minutes of the executive council of the Research Foundation. Subsequent donations have included historical correspondence and reports, as well as more recent information documenting UConn 200 programs and similar activities.
Access
The collection is open and available for research.
Provenance and Acquisition
The collection was transferred to the University Archives by the Foundation in 1980.
History
The University of Connecticut Research Foundation, established by statute in 1945, serves as the major advocate for research for all campuses of the University, except the University of Connecticut Health Center, and manages all intellectual property of the University.
Additional information and the current activities of the Office of the Vice President for Research is available on their website.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of the minutes of the executive council of the Research Foundation. Subsequent transfers have expanded the documentation to include historical correspondence and reports, as well as records documeting programs such as UConn 2000.
Archives (institutions); Annual Reports; Reports; Minutes (administrative records); Administrative records; Correspondence; Photographs; Clippings (information artifacts); University of Connecticut; University of Connecticut
- Series I: Executive Council Meeting Minutes, 1950-1993
  - 1950-1974 (Box 5)
  - 1975-1979 (Box 6)
  - 1980-1982 (Box 7)
  - 1983-1986 (Box 8)
  - 1987-1990 (Box 9)
  - 1991-1993 (Box 10)
- Series II: Historical Records, 1940s-1990s
  - Correspondence, Minutes, Reports (history, origins), 1940s-1980s (Box 1)
  - UConn 2000, Programs, Research Advisory Committee, Correspondence, Minutes, 1970s-1990s (Box 2)
- Series III: Annual Reports, 1963-1993
  - Annual reports, 1963-1980 (Box 3)
  - Annual reports, 1981-1993 (Box 4)
- Series IV: 2014 Addition, 1997-2001
  - Annual Reports, 1993-1997 (Box 2014.0082_1)
    Scope and Content Note
    financial reports for the University of Connecticut Research Foundation from 1993-1997.
  - Minutes, 1994-2001 (Box 2014.0082_2)
    minutes of the Storrs Reasearch Advisory Council from the fiscal years of 1994-1995, 1997-1998, and 2001.
  - Clippings, photographs, undated, 1986-1996 (Box 2014.0082_3)
    news clippings from various publications about various topics including the proposed tech park. Photographs from the construction of Celeron Square. A Statement of Policy on Interaction between the University of Connecticut and the Public and Private Sectors.